KAMALJEET SINGH

Web Developer

ABOUT ME

Hey there, I am a creative Web Developer with a positive attitude, open mindset, and a passion for building and designing websites. With previous experience in the tech field, I have learned to thrive under high pressure environments with firm deadlines. I look forward to opportunities where I can contribute my skills and collaborate with a team to create quality projects.

+1 519 984 8225

kamaljeetsingh1648@gmail.com #31-2136 Wyandotte Street West, Windsor, ON N9B 1J9.

Check out my portfolio here: https://kamaljeet-portfolio.herokuapp.com

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE



Full Stack Web Developer – [Apr2021 – Present]

Freelance, Windsor, ON

- Create and maintain websites for small businesses such as restaurants, educational institutions, gyms etc.
- Use search engine optimization (SEO) best practices to optimize the website for organic search
- Produce dynamic user-interfaces through comprehensive research and prototype development
- Manage and execute multiple projects concurrently to meet tight deadlines
- Build custom websites using Bootstrap and WordPress, including custom plug-ins and filters
- Function with clients to develop layout, color scheme for their website and implement it into a final interface design

Software Developer – [July 2019 – March 2021]



JD Norman Industries, Windsor, ON

- Acquired hands on experience in HTML5/CSS3 development and Node.js, Angular JS, React and responsive design
- Guaranteed the technical feasibility and optimum functioning of the company's design features that accelerated load-time by 26% and improved site stickiness by 41%
- Administered full lifecycle of software development for various projects with on-time delivery while staying 9% under budget
- Designed and maintained the e-commerce website of the company
- Built the user validation forms using the RESTful services for sending the data to the server
- Updated the company's e-commerce website effectively thus guarantying high traffic and generating a 21% increase in the company's sales revenue

Web Developer – [July 2018 –June 2019]

Venus Web Media, Ludhiana, India



- Made e-commerce websites and tested the code on multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatibility and fixed bugs
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs and cross-browser compatibility
- Acquired extensive experience working in Agile methodologies
- Functioned with clients to develop layout, color scheme for their website and implemented it into a final interface design
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed

Additional WORK EXPERIENCE

Customer Relations Associate – [Nov 2021 – Present]

HGS Canada, Windsor, ON



- Obtain client information by answering telephone calls and verifying information
- Determine eligibility by comparing client information to requirements
- Establish policies by entering client information
- Inform clients by explaining procedures, answering questions and providing information
- Improve quality results by adhering to standards and guidelines
- Accomplish sales and organization mission by completing related results as needed

EDUCATION and TRAINING



Master of Engineering in Computer Science – [June 2018]

Punjab Technical University, India

Become a Full-Stack Web Developer - [Jan 2021]

LinkedIn Learning

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development Technologies SASS JavaScript **Bootstrap** HTML5 CSS Angular **JSON NODE JS REACT JS EXPRESS JS Databases** MongoDB **Firebase** MySQL **Tools** Drupal WAMP/XAMP **GIT** NPM WordPress Integrated Development Environment **VS CODE** Atom **SUBLIME** Application Program Interface (API) **Twitter** Google Drive OneDrive DropBox **OAuth**